Oleg Pyzhcov

Highlights

- Over 4 years of experience in software development
- Good understanding of typed functional programming principles
- Able to quickly learn new libraries and techniques of development

Skills

Programming languages: Scala, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C++

Libraries: Cats, Scalaz 7, Shapeless, ScalaTest, ScalaCheck, React, Mocha

Tools: SVN, Git, SBT, Maven, Gulp.js, Webpack

Databases: H2, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Experience

Full-stack Engineer @ Intetics Minsk

(May 2016 - present time)

NuORDER

B2B eCommerce system connecting brands and retailers across the world

- Tools and Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, React
- Primary Responsibilities: development, testing.
- Key Contributions:
 - o Fixed high-priority issues in a short time.
 - Optimized a number of slow database queries and inefficient algorithms, providing speed-ups up to 10x on average cases and greatly reducing memory usage.
 - Implemented features requiring refactoring throughout the entirety of a dynamically typed code.

Software Engineer @ CIB Software IOOO

(April 2014 – May 2016)

CIB webRec

Canvas-based SPA for rich document editing with support for embedding

- Tools and Technologies: TypeScript, Gulp, React, HTML5 Canvas (2D), Java, Jersey
- Primary Responsibilities: prototyping, planning, architecture, coding, testing, docs.
- Key Contributions:
 - Initial prototyping and design proposals
 - Introduced TypeScript, React and Gulp
 - o Proposed and implemented an extensible architecture for complex domain logic
 - Played a significant role in project planning and management
 - o Developed end-to-end testing framework for ease of automated testing.

CIB jRec 2

Embeddable component for rich document (RTF) editing

- Tools and Technologies: Java, Swing
- Primary Responsibilities: coding, testing.
- Contributions: Maintenance (bug fixes, tests)

Personal open-source libraries:

better-monadic-for (https://github.com/oleg-py/better-monadic-for)

A plugin for Scala compiler that changes desugaring of for-comprehensions, providing a number of quality-of-life improvements for usage with monadic types (e.g. destructuring and monadic recursion).

Received very positive community feedback (280 stars in 7 months, mentioned in FP for Mortals book).

meow-mtl (https://github.com/oleg-py/meow-mtl)

A companion for cats-mtl library providing classy optics and cats-effect based MTL type class instances. Heavy shapeless usage, but optimized for compile-time performance.

Community contributions:

Monix (https://monix.io)

Contributor since Jan 2018. One of top contributors at current time.

Proposed redesign of Iterant class which lead to proper resource-safety support and performance improvements.

Cats-effect (https://typelevel.org/cats-effect)

Contributor since Jan 2018.

Influenced a number of design decisions that lead to improved user experience, such as automatic shifting, extension methods, convenience constructors for abstractions like Ref and support for streaming types for type classes.

StackOverflow

4,000+ reputation (https://stackoverflow.com/users/2758343/oleg-pyzhcov)

Education

Bachelor of Science

Belarusian State University, Mechanics and Mathematics Faculty, Minsk, Belarus (2011-2016)